Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Praeger Collection of Scores, circa 1829-1891
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Keyboard works, 1837-1891, I.; Item 001-369
  - Piano reductions, 1853-1890, D.; Item 342-370
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trauermarsch, C minor Trauermarsch: [in C minor] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 367)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2]. Following title: No. 7. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trauermarsch, D minor Trauermarsch = Funeral march [in D minor] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Funeral march (Box 8, Item 368)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2]. At head of title: No. 3. Caption: Scored for Grd Orchestra. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trauermarsch, F♯ minor Trauermarsch: [in F♯ minor], arranged for grand orchestra / [18--], 6 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Additional title on cover: Funeral march for gd. orchestra (Box 8, Item 369)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. At head of title: No. 13. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Zigeunermarsch = Gipsy march / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Gipsy march (Box 8, Item 370)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: No. 5. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
- Chamber works with piano, 1837-1891, II.; Item 371-397
  Arranged into five subseries:
  A. Violin and piano
  B. Viola and piano
  C. Violoncello and piano
  D. Piano trios
  E. Piano quartets
  - Violin and piano, 1837-1891, A.; Item 371-381
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Adagio con affetto; Romanze / 1837, 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 29 cm. (Box 8, Item 371)
      First work for violin and piano; second work for piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete: large section torn from bottom right of page. Top of p. [1]: 12 Oct 1837; right margin of p. [2]: 21 Nov 1837. At beginning of first system, violin appears to be crossed out and replaced with voce.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Allegretto scherzando, violin, piano Allegretto scherzando: for violin and piano / [18--], 1 ms score (6 p.); 35 cm. + 1 ms. part ([3] p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 372)
      For violin and piano. Title from violin part cover. Holograph (Ink). "Composed for & dedicated to I.M. Abbott Esqre (Birmingham)"--Cover.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Berceuses, violin, piano Berceuse pour violin & piano / [18--], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 35 cm. + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 30 cm. (Box 8, Item 373)
      For violin and piano. Title from violin part caption. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on violin part.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Cavatinas, violin, piano, A major Cavatina in A for violin and piano / [18--], 1 ms. score (5 p.) + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 374)
      For violin and piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Cavatinas, violin, piano, E major Cavatina (E) pour violon & piano / [18--], 1 ms. score (7 p.) + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 375)
      For violin and piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on violin part, p. 4, 5, 7 of score.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Elegies, violin, piano, D minor Elegy for violin & piano / 1891, 1 ms. score (3 p.); 35 cm + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 376)
      For violin and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1891.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Romances, violin, piano, D major Romanza for violin & piano [in D major] / [18--], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 377)
      For violin and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. Correction on insert pasted on p. [1].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Romances, violin, piano, E major Romanza for violin & piano in E major / [18--], 1 ms. score (5 p.) + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 378)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Romances, violin, piano. Selections Three romances for violin and piano / [18--], 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 379)
      For piano. Title from bottom of p. [1]. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2, 4].
      Contents: No. 1: [untitled] -- No. 2: Elegy -- No. 3: [untitled].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 1, D major Sonata for violin & piano, no. 1 in D major / [18--], 1 ms. score (17 p.); 31 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 29-31 cm.; Alternate title: First sonata for violin & piano (Box 8, Item 380)
      For violin and piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Both parts for violin, one in a different hand.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 2, A minor Second sonata for violin and piano in A minor / 1885, 1 ms. score (22 p.) + 1 ms. part ([6] p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 381)
      For violin and piano. Manuscript (Ink). Title page: 9th May 1885.
  - Viola and piano, 1885-1888, B.; Item 382-386
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Elegies, viola, piano, E minor Elegy for viola and piano / 1885, 1 ms. score (4 p.) + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Item 382)
      For viola and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on viola part. Caption: 11/7 1885.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Lamentation, viola, piano Lamentation: viola & piano / 1885, 1 ms. score (3 p.); 35 cm. + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 31 cm. (Box 9, Item 383)
      For viola and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1885.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Morceau, viola, piano, C minor Morceau pour viola & piano: Allegro / 1888, 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 31 cm. (Box 9, Item 384)
      For viola and piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. Caption: 3 June 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Romances, viola, piano, C major Romanza for viola & piano / 1885, 1 ms. score ([3] p.) + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Item 385)
      For viola and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 12/7 1885.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Sweet sorrow: viola & piano / 1888, 1 ms. score (5 p.); 31 cm. + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 30 cm. (Box 9, Item 386)
      For viola and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 12/7 1888.
  - Violoncello and piano, 1891, undated, C.; Item 387-392
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Allegro, violoncello, piano, E minor Allegro [for violoncello and piano] / [18--], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 9, Item 387)
      For violoncello and piano. Title from initial tempo marking. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Elegies, violoncello, piano, A minor Elegy for violoncello & piano / 1891, 1 ms. score (3 p.) + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 31 cm. (Box 9, Item 388)
      For violoncello and piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1891.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Romances, violoncello, piano, A major Romanza for violoncello & piano / [18--], 1 ms. score ([3] p.) + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 31 cm. (Box 9, Item 389)
      For violoncello and piano. Caption title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. part (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Romances, violoncello, piano, A major (Ein Gesang) Romance pour violoncello & piano / [18--], 1 ms. score (6 p.) + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 31 cm. + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 35 cm.; At head of title: Ein Gesang fu¨r Cello u Clavier Alternate title: Title on cover of larger violoncello part: Romanze for cello & piano (Box 9, Item 390)
      For violoncello and piano. Title from cover of violoncello part. Holograph (Ink). Both parts for violoncello.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Romances, violoncello, piano. Selections Three romanzas for violoncello & piano / [18--], 1 ms. score (3, 3, 4 p.) + 1 ms. part ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Item 391)
      For violoncello and piano. Title from violoncello part cover. Holograph (Ink).
      Contents: Romanza for violoncello and piano (Adagio espressivo) [A major] -- Romanza for violoncello and piano (Moderato) [A minor] -- Pastorale [F major].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Sonatas, violoncello, piano, G major Sonata for violoncello & piano in G major / [18--], 1 ms. score ([30] p.); 36 cm. + 1 ms. part (15 p.); 31 cm. (Box 9, Item 392)
      For violoncello and piano. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink).
  - Piano trios, undated, D.; Item 393-396
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Allegro con brio, piano trio, B minor Allegro con brio / [18--], 1 ms. score (10 p.); 31 cm. (Box 9, Item 393)
      For piano, violin, and violoncello. Title from initial tempo marking. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trios, piano, strings, no. 1, C minor Trio in C moll für Piano Violino & Cello in C minor / [18--], 1 ms. score (68 p.); 34 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Only the violin part has been digitized. Alternate title: Title from cover of parts: Trio pour piano violon & violoncello en ut mineur (Box 9, Item 394)
      For piano, violin, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). "1rst trio"--Cover. Corrections on inserts pasted throughout score and parts.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trios, piano, strings, no. 2, D minor Trio in D für Piano, Violino & Violoncello / [18--], 1 ms. score (34 p.); 31 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 34 cm.; Alternate title: 2d trio for piano, violin & violoncello in D Alternate title: Second trio for piano, violin & violoncello (Box 9, Item 395)
      For piano, violin, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). "Good copy"--Cover of parts.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trios, piano, strings, no. 3, A minor IIItes Trio für Violin, Violoncello, & Pianoforte / [18--], 1 ms. score (60 p.) + 2 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Alternate title: 3rd trio for violin 'cello & piano in A Alternate title: Third trio for violin, violoncello & piano (Box 9, Item 396)
      For piano, violin, and violoncello. Manuscript (Ink). Title page: Eduard LeBrun Copiest.
  - Piano quartets, undated, E.; Item 397
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, piano, strings, F major Quatuor pour piano, violino, viola & cello in F major / [18--], 1 ms. score (36 p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Item 397)
      For violin, viola, violoncello, and piano. Title from p. 1 margin. Manuscript (Ink); p. 12-36 appear to be in Praeger's hand. Incomplete work. Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
- String chamber works, 1881-1890, III.; Item 398-419
  Arranged into two subseries:
  A. String quartets
  B. String octets
  - String quartets, 1881-1890, A.; Item 398-418
    Some of the string quartets indicate a key area, but not the mode. These works begin in the minor mode and end in the major mode of that key.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 1, E Quartette no. 1 / [18--], 1 ms. score (19 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Alternate title: String quartet no. 1 (Box 10, Item 398)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Work begins in E minor, ends in E major. Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. "Dedicated to his friend Richard Wagner"--Caption.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 2, E major Second string quartet = Zweites Streichquartett E major / [18--], 1 ms. score (25 p.); 31 cm.; Alternate title: 2d quatuor pour 2 violons, viola, & cello (Box 10, Item 399)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 3, C Quartett no. 3 for 2 violins, viola & violoncello / [18--], 1 ms. score (31 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Alternate title: String quartet no. 3 in C minor Removed to separate box due to high level of mold. (Box 17, Item 400)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Manuscript (Ink). Work begins in C minor, ends in C major. Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 4, E minor Fourth string quartet / [1890], 1 ms. score (24 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 35 cm.; Alternate title: 4th fourth string quartet (Box 10, Item 401)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 4, E minor Fourth string quartette/ 1890, 1 ms. score (17 p.); 28 x 40 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 10, Item 402)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Manuscript (Ink). "First delivery March 1 1890"--Cover label.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 5, C Fifth string-quartet in C / [18--], 1 ms. score (24 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Title from cover of parts: V. Streichquartett für 2 Violinen, Bratsche und Cello Note: score contains two pages numbered 20. (Box 10, Item 403)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Work begins in C minor, ends in C major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 6, F Sixth quartet for strings in F / [18--], 1 ms. score (25 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 11, Item 404)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Work begins in F minor, ends in F major. First violin part cover: E. LeBrun Copiest.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 7, F Seventh string quartet / 1881, 1 ms. score (20 p.); 35 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Title from cover of parts: 7th string quartet (Box 11, Item 405)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Work begins in F minor, ends in F major. Title pages of parts: E. LeBrun Copiste. Caption: 1881.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 8, A 8tes Streichquartett in A / [18--], 1 ms. score ([19] p.) + 4 ms. parts; 34 cm.; Alternate title: Achte Streichquartett in A Title from caption of parts: String quartet no. 8 (Box 11, Item 406)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink). Work begins in A minor, ends in A major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 9, C Ninth string quartet in C / 1881, 1 ms. score (20 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 36 cm.; Title at head of cover: 9tes Streichquartett in C Title from title page of parts: IX Quartett (Box 11, Item 407)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Work begins in C minor, ends in C major. Cover: 30th September 1881.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.10, C Tenth string quartet / [18--], 1 ms. score (27 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 32 cm.; Removed to separate box due to high level of mold. (Box 17, Item 408)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Work begins in C minor, ends in C major. Many pages torn or stuck together.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.12, F Zwölftes Streich-quartett in F / [18--], 1 ms. score (26 p.) + 4 ms. parts; 35 cm. (Box 11, Item 409)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Work begins in F minor, ends in F major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.13, D 13th string quartet in D / [18--], 1 ms. score (21 p.); 36 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Thirteenth string quartet in D Removed to separate box due to high level of mold. Due to fragility of the parts, only the score has been digitized. (Box 17, Item 410)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Work begins in D minor, ends in D major. Right edge of score torn, some notes are missing.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.14, A major 14th string quartett / [18--], 1 ms. score (24 p.); 28 x 40 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Fourteenth string quartett (Box 12, Item 411)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.15, A major 15th string quartet in A / [18--], 1 ms. score (18 p.); 32 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 30 cm.; Alternate title: Fifteenth string quartet in A Removed to separate box due to high level of mold. (Box 17, Item 412)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Many pages torn or stuck together.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.17, D minor 17th quartet in D minor / [18--], 1 ms. score (20 p.); 36 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 30 cm.; Alternate title: Seventeenth quartet in D minor Alternate title: 17th string quartet (Box 12, Item 413)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Manuscript (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.18, E♭ major 18th quartet in E♭ major / [18--], 1 ms. score (22 p.); 36 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Title from cover of parts: 18th string quartet Alternate title: Eighteenth quartet in E♭ major Alternate title: Eighteenth string quartet (Box 12, Item 414)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted in score.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.19, D minor Nineteenth string quartet in D minor / [18--], 1 ms. score (11 p.); 36 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31-36 cm.; Alternate title: 19 string quartet Removed to separate box due to high level of mold and fragile paper. Only the title wrapper has been digitized. (Box 17, Item 415)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Many pages are torn or stuck together.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no. 20, F minor Twentieth string quartett in F / [18--], 1 ms. score (12 p.); 38 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Alternate title: 20th string quartet (Box 12, Item 416)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Quartets, strings, no.22, D 22nd string quartet / [18--], 1 ms. score (21 p.); 38 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Twenty-second string quartet Removed to separate box due to high level of mold. (Box 17, Item 417)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Manuscript (Ink). Work begins in D minor, ends in D major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Scherzos, string quartet, C major Scherzo / 1885, 1 ms. score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Item 418)
      For 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 12/Sept 85.
  - String octets, undated, B.; Item 419
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Octet, violins (4), violas (2), violoncellos (2), C major Octett for strings (scherzo) in C major / [18--], 1 ms. score (8 p.); 35 cm. + 8 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 13, Item 419)
      For 4 violins, 2 violas, and 2 violoncellos. Caption title. Holograph score (Ink); ms. parts (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout score.
- Large ensemble works, 1880-1890, IV.; Item 420-429
  Many of these works are not listed in the Finkelman inventory.
  A. Orchestra
  B. Wind band
  - Orchestra, undated, A.; Item 420-426
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Leben, Liebe, Kampf und Sieg Leben, Liebe, Kampf und Sieg :1st symphonic poem in C / [188-?], 1 ms. score (49 p.); 32 cm. (Box 13, Item 420)
      For orchestra. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink). Original title crossed out: Der Kampf am's Leben. Accompanied by printer's label: W. Straker, Printer, Ludgate Hill and Liverpool Street.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Leben, Liebe, Kampf und Sieg Leben, Liebe, Kampf und Sieg = Life, love, strife, and victory: Symphonische Dichtung für grosses Orchester / [188-?], 1 ms. score (55 p.); 38 cm. (Box 13, Item 421)
      For orchestra. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink); with additional markings, possibly by a conductor, in blue pencil. At head of cover: Performed at the Crystal Palace, Sydenham London on the 7th Novr 1885.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Manfred: (after Byron): prelude symphonique pour orchestre / [18--], 1 ms. score ([46] p.); 36 cm. + 49 ms. parts; 34 cm. (Box 13, Item 422)
      For orchestra. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink). Cover: as played at the Crystal Palace.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trauermarsch, D minor; arr. 1st Trauermarsch = funeral march for orchestra in D minor / [18--], 1 ms. score (21 p.); 37 cm.; Alternate title: Funeral march (Box 14, Item 423)
      For orchestra. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 6.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trauermarsch, F♯ minor; arr. 2d Trauermarsch in F♯ minor / [18--], 1 ms. score (24 p.); 33 cm. + 21 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 14, Item 424)
      For orchestra. Caption title. Manuscript (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Triumphal march: for orchestra in D major / [18--], 1 ms. score (17 p.); 34 cm.; Alternate title: Introduction und Marsch (Box 14, Item 425)
      For orchestra. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Ungarischer Marsch / [18--], 1 ms. score ([12] p.) + 44 ms. parts; 34 cm. (Box 14, Item 426)
      For orchestra. Caption title. Manuscript (Ink); p. [9-12] of score appear to be in Praeger's hand. First fascicle has page numbers, second does not. The second fascicle has title 2nd trio from Ungarischer Marsch in A moll. Accompanied by 1 ins. leaf with number of parts and title, Hungarian march.
  - Wind band, 1890, undated, B.; Item 427-429
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Andantes, piano, G major; arr. Andante [in G major] / [18--], 1 ms. score (10 p.); 31 cm. (Box 14, Item 427)
      For band. Caption title. Holograph (Ink, with bar lines in blue pencil).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Day dreams, band, F minor Day dreams: [for band in F minor] / [18--], 1 ms. score (15 p.); 31 cm. (Box 14, Item 428)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Legend: for 2 flutes, 2 clarinets, 2 obois, 2 bassoons, 2 horns, & euphonium, timp ad libitum / 1890, 1 ms. score (13 p.); 31 cm. (Box 14, Item 429)
      For band. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). At head of cover: June 1st 1890. Received in wrapper reading "2d Grand Symphonic Poem in F for full Orchestra; 1rst Quarter 1st March 1892; 2d Quarter 1st June 1892" in fulfillment of Praeger's contract with Lord Dysart.
- Vocal works, 1829-1891, V.; Item 430-476
  This series includes Praeger's settings of works by writers such as Emanuel Geibel, Heinrich Heine, Theodor Körner, and Henry Wadsworth Longfellow; as well as songs featuring Praeger's own lyrics.
  A. Solo songs
  B. Duets
  C. Part-songs and choruses
  D. Opera excerpts
  - Solo songs, 1829-1890, A.; Item 430-466
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Ach, wie Klopft mit heissen Schlägen Duett aus der Oper die Bergknappen / [18--], 1 ms. score (12 p.); 29 cm.; First line of text: Ach, wie Klopft mit heissen Schlägen (Box 14, Item 430)
      For 2 voices and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Above vocal line, p.1: Konrad; p. 2: Röschen. Some instrument names indicated throughout the piano line.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Alone on the shore / 1836, 1 ms. score ([6] p.); 31 cm. (Box 14, Item 431)
      For medium voice and piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Cover: Septembr 1836.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. The anchor's weighed / [18--], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 31 cm. (Box 14, Item 432)
      For medium voice and piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Correction on insert pasted on p. [1].